Guide to the Carol Kammen papers, 1973-2011.
Kammen, Carol papers, 1973-2011.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carol Kammen papers, 1973-2011.
4295
Carol Kammen, 1937-.
33.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, typscripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Personal and professional papers and student papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University history professor and specialist in upstate New York history.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal and professional papers and student papers. Student papers were written by students in Professor Kammen's History 126 course in response to assignments calling for newspaper and archives research; and for interviews regarding student life, folklore, and slang. Papers are journal entries, memoirs, or critiques of campus life.
Pen and certificate commemorating the signing of legislation creating the New York State freedom trail program, 1997. Scrapbook compiled by students in summer 2004 CAU course. Correspondence with Heriberto Dixon and file on Cayuga land claims. Correspondence relating to New York State history, and letters from Indonesia and East Timor. Files on "Cornell: Glorious to View," and files and unused materials for "First Person Cornell." Photograph album from a trip to China, Dec. 1982-Jan. 1983, with pictures of Beijing, Loying, Wuxi, Soujo, and the Li River.
Files on being a local historian, including letters, book contracts, invitations to speak, and responses, 1979-2012; research files from "Part & Apart"; and research files relating to Cornell women's history.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kammen, Carol, 1937-.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
College students--New York (State)--Ithaca--Social life and customs.; College students--Attitudes.; College students--Conduct of life.; College students' writings, English--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Folklore--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Closed until January 1, 2035 unless authorized by donor.
CONTAINER LIST
- Professional Papers
  - sealed (Box 1-17)
  - Sam MacNeil, Assemblyman, files (Box 18)
  - sealed (Box 19)
  - History News questionnaire reponses, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Municipal and Local Historian reports to Albany, 1985 (Box 22)
  - County Historian reports to Albany, 1986 (Box 23)
  - County Historian survey, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Historian articles/materials, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Ithaca Centennial, 1988-1989 (Box 25-26)
  - sealed (Box 27-33)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1998 (Box 38)
  - New York State Assembly Bill and pen, 10/28/1999 (Box 55)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1997 (Box 62)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2005 (Box 63)
  - Photo album (China), 1982-1983 (Box 64)
  - Correspondence/subject files, 1973-2011 (Box 65-66)
  - Research files on Cornell women's history and research files from "Part & Apart" (Box 67-69)
  - Files on being a local historian, 1979-2012 (Box 70)
- Student Papers
  - Freshman papers, Spring 1988 (Box 21)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Spring 1989-Fall 1989 (Box 34)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Spring 1993-Fall 1994 (Box 35)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Fall 1995 (Box 36)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Fall 1996 (Box 37, 39)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Spring 1997 (Box 40)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Spring 1995 (Box 41)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Fall 1997 (Box 42)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Spring 1998 (Box 43)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Fall 1998 (Box 44)
  - Freshman papers and projects, Spring 1999 (Box 45)
  - Student information cards, 1999 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Student Papers and projects: Jordana Beren, Michael L. Bronstein, Nick Della Valle, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Student Papers and projects: Rachel Cohen-Stevens, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Student Papers and projects: Julie DiMichele, Tony Fracasso, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Student Papers and projects: Beth Fuller, Adam Hersly, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Student Papers and projects: Chau-Jean Lin, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Student Papers and projects: Abigail Miller, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Student Papers and projects: Joni Rabiner, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Student Papers and projects: Regina Nannette Rennix, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Student Papers and projects: Bill Schuerman, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Student Papers and projects: Meredith Silverman, Stewart A. Wight, Benjamin E. Wolfe, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Student Papers and projects: Kari Zarzecki, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified student survey, Spring and Fall 1999 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Kammen, Carol: Printed statement, Diskette, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Abraham, Robin, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Berthold, Maggie, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Chen, Benjamin, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Contino, Chad, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Feder, Gail, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Gaulliere, Claudio, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Goldstein, Rachel D., Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Horne, Allison, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Hunt, Natalie, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Lawrence, Amy, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - McQuade, Scott, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Ovshey, Natan, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Smith, Alicia, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Wise, Matt, Spring 2000 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - [Anna] :Survey, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Brickner, Ben, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Brooks, Stephen, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Cajina, Ana, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Carroll, Robert, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - [Christina] :Survey, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Chu, Robert, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Correa, Joseph, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Cox, Garrett, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Crispell, Jill, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Curtin, Maeve Mara, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Fabriczi, Monika, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Fives, Theresa, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Goldberg, Rachel, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Israni, Polly, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Lloyd, David, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Lowe, Steve, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Marr, Ivy, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Pham, Monica, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Smith, Hillary, Fall 2000 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Aeyeung, Elaine, Spring 2001 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Auyeung, Grace, Spring 2001 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Crispell, Jill, Spring 2001 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Curtin, Maeve Mara, Spring 2001 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Gingerich, Natalie, Spring 2001 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Harro, Molly, Spring 2001 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Haupt, Jennifer, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Horne, Allison, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Hunt, Nathalie, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Kim, Richard, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Lee, Joanne, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Lindauer, Sarah, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Marr, Ivy, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Marx, Emily B., Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Nachod, Justin, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Pham, Monica, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Pollak, Emily, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Schuldt, Jon, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Shimizu, Koh, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - [John], Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - [Monika], Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, Spring 2000 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Brandon Gargiulo, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Mollye Levy, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Jillian Mikolajczyk, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Alex Mikszewski, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - S. Christopher Mullins, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Jason Oswalt, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Richard Laurence Rohl, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Ashley St. Amand, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Daniel Schudroff, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Karl Stauderman, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Bethany Tong, Fall 2001 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Armstrong, David, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Bachrach, Peter, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Gargiulo, Brandon, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Mikolajczyk, Jillan, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Mikszewski, Alex, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Mullins, Christopher, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Oswalt, Jason, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Rohl, Richard L., Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - St. Amand, Ashley, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Schudroff, Daniel, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Seigerman, Daniel, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Carolyn Kay, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Stauderman, Karl, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Tong, Bethany, Fall 2001 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Ashford, Adrienne, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Bartolomeo, Andrea, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Amanda, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Chalfin, Eric, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Collica, Larry, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Eskenazi, Mark Glenn, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Filippone, Lea, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Finan, Eric, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Laufer, Deanna, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Li, Monica, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Marcella, Marc, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Nagesh, Gautham, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - O'Hara, Kimberly, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Panzalan, Blesserene, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Rabinowitz, Joseph, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Striepe, Kevin, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Tyhach, Matthew, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Yerden, Danielle, Spring 2002 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Bellante, Jon, Fall 2002 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Cape, John, Fall 2002 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Chasalow, Elizabeth, Fall 2002 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Fraser, Alexis M., Fall 2002 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Pridgen, Colyar, Fall 2002 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Tetrick, Josh, [Fall 2002] (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Young, Heather A., Fall 2002 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Cornell crew research project: Seung-jae Bang, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Cornell crew research project: Orly Bertel, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Cornell crew research project: Robyn Ellerbrock, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Cornell crew research project: Christina Galati, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Cornell crew research project: Karin Holmberg, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Cornell crew research project: Janet Jeon, Fall 2002 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Cornell crew research project: Yumiko Kinugawa, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Cornell crew research project: Jordan Leen, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Cornell crew research project: Abby Lin, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Cornell crew research project: Chase MiraDiane Pflug, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Cornell crew research project: Eric Rittmeyer, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Cornell crew research project: Loren Rosenberg, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Cornell crew research project: Rebecca Silverman, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Cornell crew research project: Jamie Tsuzuki, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Cornell crew research project: Jennifer Yao, Spring 2005 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence and files, 1974-1998 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence and files, 1999-2004 (Box 59)
  - First Person Cornell files and manuscripts (Box 60)
  - The Cornell Campus: Glorious to View (Box 60-61)
  - First Year Writing Seminar files, 1991-2006 (Box 61)